<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proposals humbly offered to consideration, for collecting the duties of subsidy and aulnage at the mills</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B43726</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">625106345</idno>
  <idno type="VID">211315</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240867604</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 625106345</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocn 625106345</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P3753C</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B43726)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 211315)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2970:5)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proposals humbly offered to consideration, for collecting the duties of subsidy and aulnage at the mills</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Textile factories --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Textile industry --  Taxation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:211315:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:211315:2"/>
            <head>Proposals Humbly Offered To Consideration, for Collecting the Duties of <hi>Subsidy</hi> and <hi>Aulnage</hi> at the <hi>Mills.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>ALL Broad-Cloaths, Kersies, Bayes, Sayes, Serges, Perpetuanoes, Cottons, Cloth-Rashes, Flannels, Freezes, Stuffs, and other Woollen Commodities (except <hi>Colchester</hi>-Bayes, <hi>Norwich</hi>-Stuffs, and some other few Commodities) are brought to the <hi>Fulling-Mills</hi> to be Fulled or Scowred; after which, they are immediately capable of being <hi>Sealed</hi> by the <hi>Aulnager.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And for those other Commodities, as <hi>Colchester</hi>-Bayes, <hi>Norwich</hi>-Stuffs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not brought to <hi>Mills,</hi> the Duty to be Paid at the <hi>Halls</hi> of the <hi>Corporations,</hi> or other places, where those Goods usually have been brought to be Sealed with the Seal of Content.</p>
            <p>So that if it be <hi>Provided</hi> for by <hi>Law,</hi> That the <hi>Aulnager</hi> do receive the <hi>Kings Subsidy,</hi> and <hi>Aulnagers Fee,</hi> at the said <hi>Mills, Halls,</hi> and <hi>Places;</hi> and have Powers to <hi>Compel</hi> the <hi>Clothier</hi> to the payment of it there; It may be provided by the same <hi>Law,</hi> that no <hi>Search</hi> or <hi>Seizure,</hi> be made of the said Commodities, after they come from the <hi>Mills, Halls,</hi> and Places aforesaid.</p>
            <p>By which Means, no <hi>Draper, Mercer, Packer, Merchant,</hi> or <hi>Others,</hi> will be lyable to Searches or Seizures; and this Method is hoped, will An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer all the Objections against the present Way, or <hi>Manner</hi> of <hi>Collecting</hi> these Duties, which is used as the Great <hi>Argument,</hi> for taking away the Ancient Duties upon all Woollen Manufactures, save what are Exported; which if Confined to those Exported only, will certainly very much Lessen Their Majesties <hi>Right,</hi> and the Interest of those Claiming under the Crown: For,
<list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>I.</hi> This Way <hi>Answers</hi> all the Ends of that <hi>BILL,</hi> by ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king away <hi>Searches</hi> and <hi>Seizures,</hi> after the Goods come from the <hi>Mills</hi> or <hi>Halls.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>II.</hi> It preserves the whole Duties, whereas the <hi>BILL</hi> would Destroy <hi>Two Thirds,▪</hi> or <hi>One Half</hi> at least.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>III.</hi> It lays the Duty upon the Persons, which ought to Pay it, <hi>viz.</hi> The <hi>Clothiers,</hi> as 'twas always Designed and Practiced.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>This <hi>Regulation,</hi> the Persons Interested humbly submit to Consideration; and if the <hi>Wisdom</hi> of the <hi>Parliament</hi> shall think sit to put it into that <hi>Method</hi> of <hi>Management</hi> and Collection, they shall be willing to acquiesce therein, and never refused any Proposition for making the <hi>Way</hi> of <hi>Collecting</hi> as <hi>Easie</hi> to the People as might be.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>